Karan Kapoor

NID Alum | Senior Product Designer | Figma Trainer

Experienced Product Designer with 6 years of expertise across the full design lifecycle, from product design to research to design systems and team leadership.

I've also conducted design workshops at leading companies, studios, & institutes in India and abroad, notable clients - IIM-A, Shaadi.com, IIT-M, Indiana University, etc.

Work Experience

Keka HR · (B2B SaaS) · Senior Product Designer

Mar 2024 - Present

- Leading the design for revenue growth for products like Social wall, Surveys, Award programs, Helpdesk, Employee check-ins used by more than 1.2 million employees globally.
- Talking to users and the leadership team to come up with growth opportunities and revenue channels.
- Boosted the usage of employee wish feature from 5k users wishing 15k users to 31k users 116k users.

Immertive Pvt. Ltd. · XR Design Intern · Master's Project

Aug 2023 - Feb 2024

• Designed a cost effective virtual training platform for hospitals and institutions to spread their educational initiatives in remote areas.

Looppanel (B2B SaaS) · Product Designer

Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

- Conducted interviews & usability tests to identify core user problems and map them with business opportunities.
- Led the end to end design of features like Project summaries, Bulk note tagging, Zoom bot to drive revenue growth.

Independent Product Designer & Figma Trainer

Apr 2020 - Present

- Helping B2C, B2B startups in achieving PMF through design, research, and prototyping. Launched 20+ MVPs so far.
- Conducting Figma training and design workshops across India. Clients include IIM-A, IIM-B, IIT-M, Indiana University, and more.

Obvious · Product Designer

May 2021 - Sept 2021

- Designed features like leave tracking, auto approval, and geography-based leave calendar for Pause (#3 Product of the day on Product Hunt), a B2B leave management tool used by 50+ clients globally.
- Redesigned 3+ core user flows merchants for Grab-Singapore used by 1M+ merchants while collaborating with the user research and product leadership team.

Aphelia Innovations · Product Design Lead

Mar 2020 - Apr 2021

- Led design and launch of 5+ products and MVPs in health tech and developer experience sectors.
- Grew the design team to 4 and introduced frameworks to streamline project pipelines.

Guesthouser · Product Designer

Jun 2019 - Mar 2020

- Redesigned the booking and housekeeping apps used by ~100k people to increase user engagement, trust, and bookings on the platform.
- Created and launched a Design System for internal tools and user facing apps to reduce the development time for new features by 50%.

Info

kadankapoor.com

linkedin.com/in/karankapoorux

karan26796@gmail.com

+91 99719 80900

Education

National Institute of Design • M.Des (HCI)

Bharati Vidyapeeth's College of Engineering • B.Tech (ECE)

Skills

Design

Product Design · User Research · Usability
Testing · Project Management · 3D
Prototyping

Public Speaking and Training

Corporate Figma Training · Design Mentorship

Tools

Design, Development & No Code

Figma · Webflow · Framer Sites · Blender · Sketch · Touch Designer · ProtoPie · Adobe Suite

Code

ReactJS · Typescript · Arduino · HTML & CSS

Volunteering

Figma Community Advocate

Nov 2020 - Present

ADPList Mentor

Feb 2021 - Present

Talks & workshops

Road to UX India'24: Design to Code with

Figma for Product Managers: IIM-Ahmedabad, IIM-Sambalpur, IIM-Shillong

Figma design workshop : IIT-Madras, FLAME University, Indiana University

Design consulting: Zuddl, Shaadi.com